# Ansh Mourya | github | linkden | twitter | portfolio

9167220139 | anshmourya657@gmail.com | Mumbai, Maharashtra

# Summary

Two years plus of Full Stack Engineer Experience in MERN stack. Demonstrated ability to develop efficient, secure, and user-friendly front-end applications. I am looking to expand my skillset in the role of Full stack development.

# **Experience**

# Levitation Infotech - Noida, UP | Full Stack Developer | 02/2024 - Present

- Led the entire project from scratch, managing client interactions and requirements effectively.
- Designed and developed a scalable website ecosystem for artworks and artists.
- Successfully migrated data worth ₹1 crore from SQL to NoSQL databases, ensuring data integrity and performance.

# Javeo-Traveller | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Software Developer Intern | 09/2023 - 02/2024

- Architected and executed the development of a dynamic tourism website, leveraging React, Node.js, and MongoDB, resulting in a 40% increase in user engagement and a 25% boost in conversion rate.
- Conducted, bug fixing, and code refactoring.
- Optimized webpage rendering speed by 70% and implemented automated builds, leading to a 25% improvement in development velocity.

### SpineHealth - Freelance | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Full Stack Developer | 08/2023 - 09/2023

- Developed dynamic websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, resulting in a 25% increase in customer engagement through improved user experience and interactive features.
- Developed RESTful APIs services using ASP.NET Core and Node.is.
- Created a patient-centered web app for tracking and feedback, resulting in a 39% reduction in response time.

### 4thwallstudios - Freelance | Mumbai, Maharashtra | Frontend Developer | 08/2023 - 08/2023

 Developed a highly optimized website with interactive components, leading to a 40% increase in customer retention and a 15% revenue boost.

# **Projects**

# Swing - A Food Website | Link | June 2023 - July 2023|

- Skills: ReactJS, Stripe Integration, Google Auth, Passport JS.
- I created a food website (Swing) with an advanced filter and secure Stripe payment.
- Implemented Google Auth and Passport JS for user safety
- Simplified food discovery and ordering process.
- Achieved a delightful dining experience for users.

### Attendance Tracking Website for Students and Teachers | February 2023 - March 2023

- Built attendance-taking web platform using React, Express, and MySQL. Teachers can take attendance, and view students.
- Analytics. Students can track attendance and progress. Automated Attendance-taking process reduced teachers' time by 30%.

# Access Previous Year Paper, Going Paperless | March 2021 - April 2021

- Developed a web-based platform with React and Next.js to increase the efficiency of previous exam paper access: search/filtering, feedback, and issue reporting.
- Node.js is used for the backend, and AWS is used for data storage. The result was a reduction in paper usage by 50%—years.

### **Education**

Prahladrai Dalmia Lions College | Mumbai, Maharashtra | BSc (Bachelor of Science) in IT | 03/2024

#### **Technical**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Javascript, React, Nextjs14,

Backend: NodeJs, ExpressJs,

**Database**: MongoDB **Tools:** Git, Github